# **Brenda Thompson**

Hollis, NH 03049

Phone: (603) 759 6864 | Email: thompsonbrendajean@gmail.coml LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/brenda-thompson

| GitHub: https://github.com/BrendaTH | Portfolio: https://brendath.github.io

### **Summary**

Experienced software engineer with a Bachelor of Science in computer science and mathematics. Recently (September 2019) earned a certificate from the University of New Hampshire in Full Stack Development. Maintains an enthusiasm for many different technologies and languages, and a generalist approach in career development. Learns quickly and is goal oriented. US Air Force veteran.

#### **Technical Skills**

Experience in networking, embedded systems, C, micro-code, Bidirectional Forwarding Detection (BFD), fast path, hash tables, High Availability, PHP, JavaScript, React, Agile, Linux. Skilled in remote work with geographically diverse groups.

## **Relevant Experience**

Ericsson, Acton, MA

Software Engineer, 2014 – 2018

- Member of Engineering (2014 2018) Software developer/Agile scrum lead on HTML5 video client on browser. Written in JavaScript with Selenium unit tests.
- Member of Professional Services Team (Azuki Systems, purchased by Ericsson, 2012 -2014) Delivered Cablelabs OLCA based (Online Content Access Specification) Service Provider (in PHP) part of Azuki's overall authentication strategy.

#### CISCO Systems Inc, Boxborough, MA

Software Engineer, 2000 – 2011

- METRO-E Team (2010 2011) L2 RIB (Routing Information Database) for OTV (Overlay Transport Virtualization) project on ASR1k Router. Responsibilities included high availability (HA) support, event manager, and database redistribution, client database registration, and debug/logs/statistics. All code was written in C for CISCO IOS and required white box unit tests to be written at the same time.
- Advanced Network Transport Team (2006 2010): Platform independent Bidirectional Forwarding Detection (BFD) – written in C for IOS. Included BFD HA for the 6500/7600 Routers. Also supplied guidance and point of contact support for MPLS technical matters for a five-member contractor team out of Chennai, India.
- ACE Health Probe Team (2005 2006): Ongoing support of Health Probes on Cisco's Application Control Engine module (ACE), a server load balancing module for the Catalyst 6500. All code written in C.
- **GSS (Global Site Selector) team** (2004 2005): Cisco's Global Server Load Balancer. Provided support for Health Probes/KALs (keep alive) to ensure the ongoing validity of the DNS answers/routes. All code was written in C++.
- CSS Fastpath Team (Arrowpoint Communications, purchased by Cisco, 2000 2004):
  Wrote Fastpath microcode for Arrowpoint/CISCO Content Services Switch (CSS) 11500,
  a stand-alone server load balancer. The Fastpath was implemented on a Vitesse IQ2000
  and written in MIPS.assembly. The Fastpath included L2 VLAN/802.1Q support, stateful
  TCP flow tracking, and network address and port translation (NAT).

### **Education**

**Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp Certificate:** University of New Hampshire, Sept 2019 -- A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars, React.

**Bachelor of Science:** Computer Science and Mathematics; UAH - University of Alabama, Huntsville, AL;